This week was truly remarkable for the
AI space. We potentially saw leaks for
the Gemini 3.0 launching next week, and
you also have the ability to actually
access that with a link that I will
leave in the description below. We also
saw the release of GLM 4.6 as a powerful
new open-source model, anthropic
unveiling Claude 4.5 Sonnet, which
they're calling their best coding model
yet. Meanwhile, the Deep Seek team
quietly rolled out with their new
Deepseek V3 alongside a new experimental
Deep Seek V3.2.
And what makes this super impressive is
the fact that how they cut API costs by
more than 50% plus using something
called sparse attention. a method that
skips over less important words and
focused only on the things that actually
matter, making it much faster and
cheaper to use without losing much
quality. Now, to be fair, Deep Seek V3.2
Experimental is practically the same as
its initial release with the Terminus
model with only slight improvements in
generation. But there is a trade-off
with the sparse attention that can
sometimes struggle with very long
context. But that's exactly what these
experimental models are for. Testing,
improving, and potentially laying the
groundwork for something bigger, like
the future with Deep Seek R2. But just
take a look at this image, which
showcases the efficiency gains with DSA
enabled with fine grain sparse attention
with minimal impact on the quality of
output. It enhances long context
performance and it's reducing compute
costs drastically in comparison to the
3.1 terminus while maintaining the
performance. You can see that it's
actually on par with the terminus model
in terms of benchmarks but being super
efficient in terms of its pricing. Here
is a look at the benchmarks test and you
can see that it is comparing the
Deepseek V3.1 Terminus model up against
the new Deepseek V3.2 to experimental
and it's practically on par with it
while being super efficient. And you got
to remember the terminus model isn't
just some typical open-source model that
would be forgotten after a couple of
days. It is a pretty remarkable model
that actually a lot of people use on a
day-to-day basis due to its performance
across various sorts of benchmarks from
general purpose benchmarks like MMLU,
GPQ, the search agent, coding
benchmarks, code agents, mathematics. It
is something that is pretty impressive
and now with this new experimental
model, it is super cheap and something
that is practically free to use. Before
we get started, I just want to mention
that you should definitely go ahead and
subscribe to the World of AI newsletter.
I'm constantly posting different
newsletters on a weekly basis. So, this
is where you can easily get up-to-date
knowledge about what is happening in the
AI space. So, definitely go ahead and
subscribe as this is completely for
free. But drum roll please because this
is the pricing structure for the
deepseek v3.2 experimental model where
it's listed at 0.028
cents with cash hit which is impressive
for 1 million input tokens and with
cashmiss it is listed at 28 cents but
for the output it is listed at 42 cents
for 1 million output tokens. And this is
probably the cheapest model that packs
the same sort of performance with
proprietary models that you will ever
see. To get started with this model,
it's fairly easy. You can access it via
their chatbot completely for free or
through their API platform. Now, it's
practically free with this pricing
structure. But say if you want to access
it locally as well, you can install it
with different quantiz models and then
you can host it with Olama or LM Studio.
You can use Kilo code as well as another
AI provider. It is something that I
personally use for coding tasks and it's
something that I would recommend because
they offer $25 worth of free credits.
And pairing it with this model, it's
going to give you unlimited usage with
AI generation. Another provider you can
use is Open Roder and this is also
another trustworthy provider. Just take
a look at the output quality though.
This is where it was capable of creating
a Minecraft clone. And this is a pretty
good-looking Minecraft clone compared to
the other generations I have seen from
other models. I also found that this
model does exceptionally well with its
front-end designing where it matches up
against something like Gemini 2.5 Pro.
And just an FOI, if you're using Kilo
Code like I am, you can easily install
it from the VS Code marketplace. And
then you can click on the API
configuration tab and select the new
DeepSseek model which is going to be
listed over here. So you can easily go
ahead and select this experimental model
and start generating with it. Let's
first start off by creating a butterfly
in SVG code. We're trying to see how
well this model is in terms of
generating SVG code proficiently and
seeing if it's able to create a
symmetrical butterfly with it. So I've
copied the code from kilo code that was
generated using the deepseek model. And
this is the SVG code I've gotten for the
butterfly and it actually looks pretty
decent in my opinion. This looks a lot
better than what I actually saw from the
terminus model which is a great step
forward somehow and it looks pretty
good. But I'm going to ask it to
actually animate this now. So, I've
gotten the code for the animation and
let's see how it actually looks. Okay,
not bad to be honest. It doesn't look
the best, but it did get somewhat of the
job done. So, I guess you can give this
a pass, but obviously it's not on par
with the Gemini model. Next up, I'm
going to have it create a SAS landing
page. And I told it to add as many
features as possible. We're testing it
on its code generation, its front-end
designing, as well as how well it is in
terms of creatively adding new features
to it. So, let's see what it actually
generates. You can see that it is now
creating the to-do list for this SAS
landing page. And this is all thanks to
Kilo Code, which it does a great job in
powering the large language model to
enhance its capabilities for code
generation. But while it's also doing
this, I wanted to actually focus on
generating a browserbased OS, which is
something that we're testing through the
chatbot. This is where we're focusing on
web-based coding and we're trying to see
how I was able to implement this
browserbased OS. So I finished the
generation with Kilo code to generate
the SAS landing page and you can see
that it took approximately only 4 cents
and this is after generating thousands
of lines of code. also testing and
optimizing the landing page and this is
the SAS landing page that we had it
generate which looks absolutely amazing
and this is what I meant with its UX
design. It is something that comes on
par with top proprietary models and this
is something that added animations the
pricing tier structure the testimonials
and a couple other things like FAQ which
passes the test for generating the SAS
landing page and it looks pretty decent.
doesn't look like a typical AI generated
web page. But to me, the SAS landing
page looks great for an open- source
model. But what impresses me more is the
pricing structure, which is only 5 cents
for this generation, which is just
insane. Looks like the browserbased OS
is also finished generating. And you can
see how many lines of code it actually
worked upon. But we can actually take a
look at it directly from the chatbot.
And there we go. We have our browser Mac
OS style uh operating system. Now, one
thing I can note is that it failed at
generating the icons, which I guess is
the only downside, but it did mimic the
Mac OS style. You have a couple of
different apps. The Finder app, you have
a Safari, which actually opens up, and
that's pretty good. It also has
generated a Mac OS terminal. There's a
notes app as well. So, I guess it did
pass this test. It would have been
better if it actually generated these
different icons, but for its price and
quality, it is truly great to see. Next
up is a prompt that testes its ability
to perform logical reasoning, sequential
problem solving, and quantitative
planning. Essentially, this is where
we're trying to send in this prompt
where we're stating that you have three
containers. One holds 8 L of water, one
holds 5 L, and one holds 3 L. You need
exactly 4 L in the 8 L container. You
can pour water between containers freely
but cannot measure partial liters
directly. Explain step by step how you
would achieve exactly four lers in the 8
L container. And you can see that with
its reasoning, it's typical deepse
reasoning. It is working on different
sorts of sequential problem solving
outcomes. And it is going to then work
on multiple steps to get the correct
answer. And it's going to carefully
evaluate this by getting the answer
where you can pour and transfer water
following the classic 853 water puzzle
step. And this is to leave exactly 4 L
in the 8 L container. And there we go.
After thinking for 77 seconds, it was
able to exactly leave 4 L in the 8 L
container. And it was able to follow
through with the correct steps to get
there. Now, overall, it did a great job
with its ability for multi-step logical
reasoning. and it was able to plan
through through the reasoning. It was
able to also use quantitative problem
solving to get the right answer which we
see over here. If you like this video
and would love to support the channel,
you can consider donating to my channel
through the super thanks option below.
Or you can consider joining our private
Discord where you can access multiple
subscriptions to different AI tools for
free on a monthly basis plus daily AI
news and exclusive content plus a lot
more. But that's basically it guys for
today's video on the Deepseek V3.2
experimental model. This gives me high
hopes for the Deepseek R2 model which
should be releasing by the end of this
year. And with this pricing structure,
it's going to be truly remarkable as to
what we are going to be able to use and
get out from the Deepseek R2 model. This
is truly an impressive experimental
model and I highly recommend that you
try it out because it's practically free
when you're using it with this pricing
structure as well as with a provider
like Kilo Code. I'll leave all these
links in the description below so that
you can easily get started. But with
that thought guys, thank you guys so
much for watching. Let me know what you
guys think. Subscribe to the second
channel, join the newsletter, join me on
the private Discord, follow me on
Twitter, and lastly, make sure you get
subscribed, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos because there is
a lot of videos that you can truly
benefit from. But with that thought,
guys, thank you guys so much for
watching. Have an amazing day, spread
positivity, and I'll see you guys fairly
shortly. is ups.